A soaring experience unlike anything you've ever seen before.
Birdy is a drama, war film directed by Alan Parker.
Two young men are seriously affected by the Vietnam War.
One of them has always been obsessed with birds - but now believes he
really is a bird, and has been sent to a mental hospital.
Can his friend help him pull through?
Birdy, played by Matthew Modine.
Sergeant Al Columbato, played by Nicolas Cage.
Doctor Major Weiss, played by John Harkins.
Mr. Columbato, played by Sandy Baron.
Hannah Rourke, played by Karen Young.
Renaldi, played by Bruno Kirby.
Birdy is a 1984 American drama film based on William
Wharton's 1978 novel of the same name.
Directed by Alan Parker, it stars Matthew Modine and Nicolas Cage.
Set in 1960s Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, the film focuses on the friendship
between two teenage boys, Birdy (Modine) and Al Columbato (Cage).
The story is presented in flashbacks, with a frame narrative depicting
their traumatic experiences serving in the Vietnam War.
Parker initially turned down an opportunity to direct, believing that the
complex book could not be successfully adapted for a feature film.
The project resurfaced in 1982 when A&M Films, a subsidiary of A&M Records, acquired the film
rights and commissioned Sandy Kroopf and Jack Behr to write the screenplay.
Upon reading the script, Parker returned as director, and the
film continued development at Tri-Star Pictures.
Principal photography began in May 1984 and concluded in August of that year.
Filming took place on locations in Philadelphia and Santa Clara, California.
The film is notable for being the first to be partially shot with the Skycam, a
computer-controlled camera system created by Steadicam inventor Garrett Brown.
The score was composed by Peter Gabriel.
Birdy opened in limited release on December 12, 1984.
It underperformed at the North American box office, grossing
only $1.4 million against a budget of $12 million.
The film received mostly positive reviews, and has an
approval rating of 83% at Rotten Tomatoes.
Birdy was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the Top Ten Films of 1984, and
won the Grand Prix Spécial du Jury prize at the 1985 Cannes Film Festival.
The tone is emotional.